Muhammad Usman Majeed

Email: 12mm123@queensu.ca Cell: (613) 770-6975 Address: 250, Bantry Avenue, Richmond Hill, ON

OBJECTIVE

Obtain a Software engineering internship within your firm where I can apply my engineering skills to gain valuable and practical professional experience. I am a hardworking, dedicated and motivated individual, who looks for exciting opportunities and I also have extensive experience in engineering, project management, design projects and mobile/web development.

EDUCATION

Computer-Software Engineering (3rd year) with Professional experience

[Sept 2013- June 2018]

Queen's University, Kingston, ON

Awards: Queen's University entrance scholarship for excellent academic performance NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Awards

Relevant Courses:

Computer Graphics, Software Specifications, Data Structures and Algorithms, Digital Systems, Computer Architecture, Object Oriented Programming (Java), Discrete Mathematics, Image Processing - computer Vision and Operating Systems.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Systems Engineer at AMD

[May 2016- Aug 2017]

Top 10 interns of the year award at AMD

- Implemented new logic for AMD powerXpress to improve responsiveness on GPU automatic power-on and power-Off this resulted in 230ms reduction in latency
- Developed internal GUI Windbg launcher tool(one of the volunteering side project)
- Worked with C/C++ for AMD Radeon's kernel mode driver.

Software Developer (Android)

[Feb 2015- Dec 2015]

FacilMD, http://www.facilmd.com/

Toronto, Ontario

- Working within the research and development engineering team to develop a mobile and web based solution for organizations in the medical industry in Ontario including the Canadian Academy of Lifestyle Medicine (CALM)
- Providing engineering support by developing algorithms for Android and iOS applications to incorporate service oriented back end data sources
- Reviewing and debugging previous coding scripts to analyze and solve issues to increase performance. Increased the previous
 website's smoothness and animation by 100% by improving the frames rates from 30 to 60
- Conducting beta-testing using patient feedback and surveys to improve the overall interface and the algorithm of the application

Software Engineering Intern

[Jan 2015- Aug 2015]

Queen's Visual Cognition labs, http://qvcl.queensu.ca/

Kingston, Ontario

- Working with the Associate Professor of Psychology at Queen's University to create real world eye tracking simulations using MATLAB algorithm. This program transforms raw eye movement data to display, analyze and visually examine patterns
- Developing a MATLAB algorithm that monitors the brain's functional capacity in Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI)
- Program assisted researchers in 15 publications and provided a road map for future implementation.
- Building programs using computer vision and natural language processing toolbox by MATLAB to inspect new and different aspects of visual cognition

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming:

- C, C++, VDHL, Arduino, Nxt Robots (Robot C), .NET, C#, SQL, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python
- Extensive knowledge of TCP/IP and network programming
- Knowledge of Databases, Data Structures and Algorithms with their practical implementation
- Rapid prototyping on Android and iOS mobile platforms

Software Applications:

- Microsoft Office Suite: Professional experience in using Microsoft Office suite
- **XCode:** Designed and prototyped application for iOS using objective-C
- MATLAB/SIMULINK: Knowledge of plotting and analyzing mathematical functions on MATLAB
- AutoCAD/SOLIDEDGE/3DsMax: Knowledge of designing 2-D and 3-D models using SOLID EDGE
- Adobe Creative suite: Knowledge of graphic designing using illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign
- Operating Systems: Proficient at using Windows, Linux, UNIX and Mac OS
- Google Play Services: Location & Context, Analytics, AdMob, Maps and Identity
- Eclipse/Android Studio: Developed Java/Android projects using Eclipse/Android Studio

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Kwak – A smartphone app and API, http://challengepost.com/software/kwak Android, Java

[May 2015- April 2015]

- Designed application with a back-end algorithm that can generate over 1 million strings of provocative statements by combing 100 different subjects, adjectives, places and articles
- A multithreaded application designed to allow efficient transition between backend and frontend
- Open source API of the algorithm made available online to Queen's School of Computing

Website Development [Dec 2014]

Languages and packages: Adobe Photoshop, HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery and Bootstrap

Disease Prevention and Control by Nanorobot Technologies

[Oct 2014- Dec 2014]

- Developed a macro scale model of Nano-Robot using Arduino
- Programmed Robot to do certain tasks involving navigation
- Modified Robot's circuitry according to our design model

2-D Game Development

[May 2014- Aug 2014]

- Developed few mini-project games using simple GUI
- Learned about arithmetic expressions and event driven programming
- Creating and manipulating animations
- Controlled different parameters like velocity, acceleration etc.

Android Navigational Application – Disability Assistance

[Jan 2014- April 2014]

- Conducted market research to analyze the currently available applications
- Created the application specifications and delivery timelines
- Worked with the team to complete the java coding
- Provided ideas and direction regarding the efficiency of the code
- Liaised with the clients as well as the faculty advisor and provided technical reports to complete development

Several other side projects available upon request

EXTRACURRICULLAR EXPERIENCE

Member: Queen's Engineering Society, IEEE, GitHub, Apple Developers, XDA Developers and Code the Change Volunteer Experience: Queen's Pakistani Student Society for Charity work, Red Cross Canada and Extreme Start-ups Sports and Hobbies: Soccer, Baseball and Fitness

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- WHIMS
- Electrical Safety Certificate
- Online certificates in: machine learning, full stack development, game development and java programming.

COVER LETTER BELOW